so invented generosity
can you speak up
so how is generosity
just in general
but the point of generosity
what makes wise and wholesome in itself
basically well the most of the most
fundamental level it is wholesome
because it involves its founded even if
a person is not aware of it
the act of generosity is basically as
it's called in the act of non
self-centeredness or selflessness or non
selfishness like when you when you when
you say when you use the word selfish
but people already have notions about
selfish and unselfish and like given if
you're non selfish you're doing it as as
your as your sort of decision and choice
so it's being selfish or not selfish
it's unarmed or not not on a not on that
fundamental level that I'm referring to
here it's kind of secondary to it
because people can selfishly engage in
acts of not selfishness but what I'm
talking about is a pure nature of the
act of generosity if you if you if you
sort of look at it and it's just just in
its in its own context it it is founded
upon non selfishness of of a genuine
kind it doesn't it doesn't it doesn't
revolve around self-centeredness so
that's what generosity is good even for
people who are selfish even for people
who do it for selfish reasons people can
be generous for selfish reasons but
still that does not cancel out the act
of generosity which is the act of non
selfishness sure on a more general level
their selfishness has taken possession
of that non selfish generosity but in
itself it still counts
obviously it's better to not be selfish
on any level so that's why selfish
generosity in itself is is good that's
it that's the sole reason
now why is Jane Austen unselfish well
that's just the nature things so
generosity in itself
you could you could and based on what I
said you can see that Austin itself it's
not that fundamental generosity itself
is good because it contains the
fundamental principle of non selfishness
so if you can tap into is a fundamental
principle of not selfishness you don't
have to be generous because you will
neither be generous in their generous
you'll go beyond selfishness even if you
if you don't give anything to anyone for
the rest your life but it's just people
who don't reach those levels of
development of their mind that kind of
freedom for them is good to even just
emulate selfishness sorry family
generosity which would then emulate
which would then contain acts of non
selfishness they are not aware of it to
what extent or whatever but in itself it
still comes it still it still matters so
basically one should be actively sort of
engaged in generosity if he has means
and an ability to do so and so on but
should not make a practice out of it
because it's only like like a second
best like if you can't really commit to
the practice and really develop your
mind directly without any intermediary
which would be the act of generosity
then yeah if you can't do those those
things more directly then focus on
generosity oh if you're not sure if
you're doing those things right you're
not keep doing generosity just in case
be generous and that's it but I guess
another thing you could add is that yeah
a person should try and do it surface ly
but an unenlightened person had no
choice but being selfish whatever he do
whatever he does it because he wants to
do it he has a desire to do so which
means he's acting selfish always but
then you have selfishness that will then
perpetuate and bring more selfishness
and then you have selfishness that can
then bring more generosity so you want
to calculate that kind of selfishness
that's why the Buddha for example would
encourage people actively think about
benefits of giving could you be reborn
in heaven and so on yeah want it and do
it doesn't matter yeah it's not super
like hundred percent pure but for where
they are at it's it's
it's good